Nishrin Khambati

Contact

Profile



(587)-897-8786



nishrin@gmail.com

Software engineer with over four years of industry experience in application development. Passionate about building with innovation. Independently learning web development.

Skills

Technical

- C++, Java
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- SQL, Database Management
- Git & GitHub

Communication

- Written Communication
- Public Speaking
- Teamwork

Work Experience

Technical Writer, Sourceress ------ Sept. 2017 - Present

- Wrote personalized, high-response outreaches to engineering and managerial candidates
- Improved existing templates and company processes
- Underwent training to improve knowledge-base of technical subjects
- Tools/Skills Used: Slack, Atlassian

Software Developer, Verdazo ------ Jul. 2013 – Aug. 2017

- Primary developer for mid-level data manipulation for the Verdazo oil and gas analytics software
- Programmed highly client-requested data grouping feature, as well as a more secure licensing format
- Contributed to User Interface design, as well as discussions on client requests and feature integration
- Researched and implemented new methods to push company's product ahead of its competitors
- Tools/Skills Used: C++, Visual Studio, Mercurial

Software Developer Intern, IBM (DB2 LUW Release Management Team) ------ May. 2011 – Aug. 2012

- Worked with the IBM DB2 Early (Beta) Programs and successfully managed over 300 participants, from setting up test environments to resolving customer inquiries and gathering feedback
- Used high-level xml to develop upon a dynamic, reporting tool to provide more accurate project and release data to managers and executives
- Managed the Release Team databases, applying SQL and basic scripting
- Tools/Skills Used: DB2, SQL, Perl

Volunteer Experience

Blog Coordinator and MeetnGeek Co-Lead, The Chic Geek ------ Oct. 2015 - Nov. 2018

- Co-led the Chic Geek's MeetnGeek, an evening event providing a high-level technical talk coupled with a networking opportunity
- Organized venues, speakers, marketing, and public relations the day of each event
- Founded the Speaker Development Program to create a system for speakers to improve upon their own skills throughout the course of MeetnGeek
- Created content for Chic Geek blog, including technical pieces and interviews
- Tools/Skills Used: Event management and public relations skills, Slack

Education

Software Engineering

(Graduated with Internship, with Distinction)

University of Calgary, Alberta 2008 - 2013

Related Projects

iPhone Photo Categorization App ------ Jul. 2012 - Apr. 2013

- Planned and developed an iOS application that automatically retrieved pictures from a user's photo gallery at set intervals, and categorized text-based and image-based pictures into separate folders.
- Researched and implemented mathematical formulas for image separation algorithm, as well as prototyped and developed the user-interface
- Tools/Skills Used: Objective C, Xcode